Finding Aid for Jack Van Coevering Papers 1928-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  - Negatives: Michigan subjects
    - Fish and fish culture
      - Bass rearing ponds, Holland Fish and Game Club, Ottawa County 1928 (Box 19)
        (no. 13-13C)
      - Dams (Box 19)
        (no. 14-14B)
      - Feeding apparatus, Paris Hatchery, summer 1932 (Box 19)
        (no. 15)
      - Fin clipping, State fish hatchery, Drayton Plains April 1949 (Box 19)
        (no. 16-16B)
      - Fish work, Meadowlane Farm near Brighton (Box 19)
        (no. 18-18B)
      - Fisheries work, seining in Huron River when low August 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 19-19B)
      - Marsh reconstruction, Sebewaing, Huron County, Oc. 1960 (Box 19)
        (no. 20)
      - Perch, gathering spawn, Reeds Lake April 10, 1930 (Box 19)
        (no. 21)
      - Perch, seining minnows, Traverse City October 1931 (Box 19)
        (no. 22-22B)
      - Stream insect work, J.W. Leonard on Au Sable 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 24-24B)
      - Lifting trout over Foote Dam with Arthur Leitz April 28, 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 25-25D)
      - Brook trout at Gangle Lake July 11, 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 26)
      - Brown trout stripping at Paris Hatchery November 14, 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 27-27B)
      - Trout cleaning, Ben Allen 1942 (Box 19)
        (no. 28-28C)
      - Trout, jaw tag and fin clip, Dave Shetter April 1938 (Box 19)
        (no. 29-29A)
      - Trout work, A.S. Hazzard and J.W. Leonard (Box 19)
        (no. 30)
      - Trout work, Hunt Creek Experiment Station, J.W. Leonard April 29, 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 31-31C)
      - Trout work, Hunt Creek Experiment Station, Dave Shetter July 14, 1939 (Box 19)
        (no. 32-32A)
    - Forests and trees
      - Birch trees June 30, 1946 (Box 19)
        (no. 33)
      - Birch trees peeled and initialed, Ocqueoc Falls May 30, 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 34-34A)
      - Black alder, Ogemaw County October 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 35)
      - Kent County, sycamore and elm intergrown (Box 19)
        (no. 37)
      - Snow gauge, Ogemaw State Forest February 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 38)
      - Frost on trees, Ogemaw State Game Refuge February 1933 (Box 19)
        (no. 41)
      - Hartwick Pines (Box 19)
        (no. 42-42A)
      - Norway flowering pine, Wilderness Park (Box 19)
        (no. 43-43A)
      - Pine seedlings, just out, Higgins Lake Nursery July 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 44)
      - Tree growing, Albert Engel, Lake City September 1957 (Box 19)
        (no. 46-46C)
      - Tree planting April 1932 (Box 19)
        (no. 47)
      - Tree with two trunks, near Ortonville July 7, 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 48)
      - Trees on Orchard Lake Road, Orchard Lake, being cut September 25, 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 49-49F)
      - Town Forest, Flint Kiwanis Club and Harry Black July 23, 1944 (Box 19)
        (no. 50-50B)
    - Forest fires and prevention
      - Forest fire, U.S. 27 north of Grayling July 31, 1933 (Box 19)
        (no. 52-52B)
    - Hunting and trapping
      - Archery tournament, Grayling June 1960 (Box 19)
        (no. 54-54B)
      - Duck marsh, Sebewaing Bay September 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 55)
      - Duck hunting, Nilo farms March 1958 (Box 19)
        (no. 55A-55C)
      - Traps (Box 19)
        (no. 56-56C)
      - Trapshooting, Paul Bunyan Club at Doc Stricker's October 1955 (Box 19)
        (no. 56E-56F)
    - Insects
      - Monarch butterfly, Aut. 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 58)
      - Collecting caddis larvae, Rudolph Johnson, White Cloud January 1938 (Box 19)
        (no. 59-59B)
      - Dragon flies September 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 60)
      - Hawk moth on Au Sable River June 21, 1942 (Box 19)
        (no. 61)
      - Mayfly June 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 62)
      - Io moth June 1951 (Box 19)
        (no. 63)
    - Lakes
      - Round Lake, north of Charlevoix (Box 19)
        (no. 67)
      - Disappearing lakes, Upper Peninsula (Box 19)
        (no. 68-68A)
      - Grand Traverse County, filled lake on U.S. 131 near Fife Lake July 30, 1933 (Box 19)
        (no. 69)
      - Half Moon Lake on Jewell property near Bitely, Newaygo County 1928 (Box 19)
        (no. 70)
      - Kent Lake July 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 71)
      - Loon Lake near Wellston August 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 72)
      - Lost Lake, Pigeon River State Forest April 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 73)
      - Lost Lake, Lost Lake Woods Club, Montmorency County August 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 74-74A)
      - Lake Michigan near Brevoort, Mackinac County August 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 75)
      - Lake Michigan and lighthouse in winter, Grand Haven 1929 (Box 19)
        (no. 76)
      - Lake Michigan and lighthouse in winter, Grand Haven 1954 (Box 19)
        (no. 78)
      - Orchard Lake and fishermen June 25, 1946 (Box 19)
        (no. 80)
      - Ottawa County beach at Grand Haven July 4, 1930 (Box 19)
        (no. 81-81B)
      - Portage Lake, Jackson County (Box 19)
        (no. 82)
      - Rush Lake, Huron County April 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 83-83A)
      - Sage Lake, Ogemaw County 1944 (Box 19)
        (no. 84)
      - Union Lake at Greggs Livery June 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 85)
      - Wabasis Lake, Kent County 1929 (Box 19)
        (no. 86)
    - Lumbering and conservation
      - Civilian Conservation Corps Camp no. 1662 Ogemaw (Box 19)
        (no. 87-87B)
      - Civilian Conservation Corps fighting fires (Box 19)
        (no. 88-88A)
      - Lumber camp, Herb Woland camp, Cheboygan County April 1937 (Box 19)
        (no. 89-89D)
      - Lumbering in Kent County 1929 (Box 19)
        (no. 90-90C)
    - Lures and equipment
      - L.L. Dickerson making trout rod March 1938 (Box 19)
        (no. 92-92C)
      - Mayfly lure (Box 19)
        (no. 93)
      - Straw man lure by Paul Young May 1932 (Box 19)
        (no. 94)
      - Fly tying, Ed Reith and group March 16, 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 96)
      - Fly tying tools (Box 19)
        (no. 97)
      - Fly and tackle box (Box 19)
        (no. 98)
    - Plants and fungi
      - Columbine May 4, 1965 (Box 19)
        (no. 100)
      - Jack in the pulpit 1951 (Box 19)
        (no. 101)
      - June berry 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 102)
      - Lobelia, blue (Box 19)
        (no. 103)
      - Marsh marigold--cowslip May 3, 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 104)
      - Mushroom September 1934 (Box 19)
        (no. 106)
      - Mushroom, shaggy mane (Box 19)
        (no. 107)
      - Pickerel weed, near Sage Lake June 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 108)
      - Trillium May 4, 1965 (Box 19)
        (no. 109)
      - Wintergreen blossom (Box 19)
        (no. 110)
    - Pollution
      - Aurora Oil Company oil break (Box 19)
        (no. 111-111A)
      - Buchanan Disposal Plant July 18, 1949 (Box 19)
        (no. 112-112B, 113)
      - Detroit River
        - Pollution 1948 (Box 19)
          (no. 114-114D)
        - Fills, etc. April 7, 1961 (Box 19)
          (no. 115-115B)
        - Oil May 10, 1959 (Box 19)
          (no. 116-116A)
        - Oil drifting down on ice October 1948 (Box 19)
          (no. 117-117A)
        - Oil soaked ducks October 1948 (Box 19)
          (no. 118-118B)
      - Erosion, Looking Glass River, Clinton County October 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 119-119A)
      - Erosion control, Ludington State Park September 1934 (Box 19)
        (no. 120)
      - Kalamazoo, Upjohn Company, disposal plant September 1949 (Box 19)
        (no. 122-122A)
      - Lake St. Clair fill-in 1954-1955 (Box 19)
        (no. 123-123B)
      - East Lansing sewage disposal plant, Dept. 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 124-124A)
      - Michigan Sugar Company, Sebewaing, water pollution October 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 125-125A)
      - Pollution lecture, Rackham Building, U of M 1948 (Box 19)
        (no. 126)
      - Pollution testing on boat (Box 19)
        (no. 127)
      - River Raisin, Monroe, water pollution (Box 19)
        (no. 128-128A)
      - St. Joseph River, Blackhawk Camp July 18, 1949 (Box 19)
        (no. 129-129A)
    - Portraits
      - Christofferson, Carl, Blaney Park November 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 131)
      - Criqui, Francis B., President MUCC (Box 19)
        (no. 132)
      - Dice, L.H. U of M Museum of Zoology December 15, 1937 (Box 19)
        (no. 133)
      - Engel, Albert, Congressman circa July 1943 (Box 19)
        (no. 134)
      - Flynn, Felix, of Cadillac July 1, 1933 (Box 19)
        (no. 135)
      - Herbert, Paul, MSU Dept. of Forestry 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 136)
      - Hickey, Joseph J. U of M, Ornithology (Box 19)
        (no. 137)
      - Hubbs, Carl, Director, Fisheries Research, U of M January 1937 (Box 19)
        (no. 138)
      - Keely, Walter, President MUCC June 20, 1943 (Box 19)
        (no. 139)
      - Kennedy, Ed, Wolf Lake Fish Hatchery, Kalamazoo, with Henry (Box 19)
        (no. 140)
      - McLouth, Don, Conservation Commissioner May 6, 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 141)
      - Miller, Volmar, President MUCC June 15, 1952 (Box 19)
        (no. 142)
      - Ruhl, Harry D., Chief, Game Division, Michigan Conservation Dept. August 12, 1960 (Box 19)
        (no. 144)
      - Stewart circa 1937 or, 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 145)
      - Sutton, George M. with J. Van Tyne at U of M August 1934 (Box 19)
        (no. 146)
      - Van Coevering, Jack November 1946 (Box 19)
        (no. 147)
      - Van Coevering, Jack June 25, 1954 (Box 19)
        (no. 148)
    - Reptiles
      - Fiddler crabs, Sea Grape Island March 1953 (Box 19)
        (no. 150)
      - Swamp tree frog (Box 19)
        (no. 151)
      - Snake, red bellied August 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 153)
      - Snapping turtle October 15, 1942 (Box 19)
        (no. 154)
      - Toad eggs April 1939 (Box 19)
        (no. 155)
    - Rivers and streams
      - Agate Falls September 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 157-157A)
      - Au Sable River 1933-1964 (Box 19)
        (no. 158A-158E)
      - Bond Falls September 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 159-159B)
      - Chocolay River Falls near Marquette October 1, 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 160)
      - Clinton River mouth June 1946 (Box 19)
        (no. 161)
      - Jordan River 1939, 1949 (Box 19)
        (no. 162-162A)
      - Kent County, ice breaking in Ken-O-Sha Creek 1928 (Box 19)
        (no. 163)
      - Leland Harbor April 29, 1963 (Box 19)
        (no. 164)
      - Straits of Mackinac June 2, 1946 (Box 19)
        (no. 165-165B)
      - Manistee River (Box 19)
        (no. 166-167)
      - Pine River Bridge at M55 November 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 168-168A)
      - Manistee River, Bill Stuck removing logs April 24, 1937 (Box 19)
        (no. 169-169B)
      - Peshekee River, Marquette County August 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 170)
      - Pere Marquette River 1933-1962 (Box 19)
        (no. 171-173)
      - Michigamme River (Box 19)
        (no. 174-174A)
      - Newaygo Sounty stream tributary to Little Muskegon near Croton 1930 (Box 19)
        (no. 175)
      - Otsego County trout stream April 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 176)
      - Ottawa County, Grand River, Grand Haven, "bloom" on the water 1929 (Box 19)
        (no. 177)
      - Paint River, near Crystal Falls July 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 178)
      - Pine River, publicly owned stretch with Conservation Commission July 1937 (Box 19)
        (no. 179-179A)
      - Rouge River, Detroit, canoe trip June 1, 1943 (Box 19)
        (no. 180)
      - Sault Ste. Marie, locks June 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 181-181A)
      - Tahquamenon River and Falls 1931-1949, 13 negatives (Box 19)
        (no. 182-187B)
    - Scenery
      - Beaver Island, St. James Harbor August 1930 (Box 19)
        (no. 189)
      - Charity Islands lighthouse July 18, 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 190)
      - Cheboygan County winter scene 1942 (Box 19)
        (no. 191)
      - Crystal Lake June 1942 (Box 19)
        (no. 192)
      - Drummond Island September 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 193-193C)
      - Fayette Harbor, Garden Peninsula May 30, 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 194-194A)
      - Port Sanilac July 21, 1956 (Box 19)
        (no. 195)
      - Grand Island July 1, 1951 (Box 19)
        (no. 196)
      - Isle Royale 1935, July 1964, 5 negatives (Box 19)
        (no. 197-198)
      - Kent County, Bear Creek in Townsend Park April 1931 (Box 19)
        (no. 199)
      - Kent County, Honey Creek April 1931 (Box 19)
        (no. 200)
      - Luce County, Lake Superior State Forest (Box 19)
        (no. 201-201A)
      - Mackinac Island August 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 202-202C)
      - Mason County, Ludington State Park July 1933, October 1934 (Box 19)
        (no. 203A-203C)
      - Copper mine north of Calumet (Box 19)
        (no. 204)
      - Wakefield open pit iron mine September 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 205)
      - Mouille Marsh 1944 (Box 19)
        (no. 206-206B)
      - Mountain Drive, Keweenaw Peninsula August 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 207-207A)
      - Muskegon County sand dunes (Box 19)
        (no. 208-208A)
      - Newaygo Desert 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 209-209B)
      - Ocqueoc Falls May 30, 1950 (Box 19)
        (no. 210-210A)
      - Otsego County winter scenes January 10, 1943 (Box 19)
        (no. 211-211A)
      - Passage Island August 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 212)
      - Pigeon River State Forest (Box 19)
        (no. 213-214)
      - Point Aux Barques July 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 215)
      - Porcupine Mountains September 1941 (Box 19)
        (no. 216-216A)
      - St. Clair Flats June 8, 1962 (Box 19)
        (no. 217)
      - Seney Refuge October 2, 1936 (Box 19)
        (no. 218-218A)
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes 1930-1962, 7 negatives (Box 19)
        (no. 219-221B)
      - Sleet storm, Otsego? 1939 (Box 19)
        (no. 222)
      - The Snows September 1940 (Box 19)
        (no. 223-223D)
      - Winter scenes 1935-1945, 5 negatives (Box 19)
        (no. 225-227B)
  - Negatives: Non-Michigan subjects
    - Alaska August-September 1947, 9 negatives (Box 19)
      (no. 228-229C)
    - Arizona, Tucson 1958, 14 negatives (Box 19)
      (no. 230-233B)
    - Bahamas March 1960 (Box 19)
      (no. 234-234B)
    - Canada
      - Banff, Alberta July 1953 (Box 19)
        (no. 235-235A)
      - Quebec August-September 1958 (Box 19)
        (no. 235B-235D)
    - Florida, fishing circa 1951-1957, 10 negatives (Box 19)
      (no. 236-242)
    - Mexico 1937 (Box 19)
      (no. 243-243I)
    - Mississippi November 1939 (Box 19)
      (no. 244-244B)
    - Missouri and Ozarks May 1939 (Box 19)
      (no. 245-245E)
    - Montana, West Yellowstone August 1951 (Box 19)
      (no. 246-246D)
    - North Carolina, March October 1954, 5 negatives (Box 19)
      (no. 247-248A)
    - North Dakota circa 1946 (Box 19)
      (no. 249-249C)
    - Oregon July 1946 (Box 19)
      (no. 250-250B)
    - Panama March 1963 (Box 19)
      (no. 250C-250E)
    - South Dakota (Box 19)
      (no. 251-251C)
    - Wyoming July 1944 (Box 19)
      (no. 252-252J)
    - Colorado or New Mexico 1939, 8 negatives (Box 19)
      (no. 253-254D)
    - Glacier Park (Box 19)
      (no. 255-255H)
- "A Brief History of Conservation in Michigan" circa 1978
  The series "A Brief History of Conservation in Michigan" (Box 20) contains the manuscript for a book of the same title completed after his move to Arizona in 1974 and prior to his death in 1978. The manuscript was never published. The subsequent folders contain the research used to produce the manuscript and are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Manuscript of history (Box 20)
  - Collected Background Information
    - Banana peel engineering notes (Box 20)
    - Curwood, James Oliver
      - Notes and Clippings circa 1970s (Box 20)
      - Photocopies of Correspondence circa 1922 (Box 20)
    - East, Ben September 28, 1968 (Box 20)
    - Herbert, Dr. Paul (interviewed 1967) (Box 20)
    - Lovejoy, P.S., circa 1935 (Box 20)
    - McGregor, Louis D. (interviewed September 26, 1968) (Box 20)
    - Michigan History circa 1930s (Box 20)
    - Michigan Indian Lore articles circa 1930s-1960s (Box 20)
    - Notebook Index 1930-1965 (Box 20)
    - Pigeon River Conservation Project 1973-1977, 2 folders (Box 20)
- Research for proposed history: Prominent Michigan Conservationists
  The Research for proposed history: Prominent Michigan Conservationists series (Boxes 20-21) contains the transcripts of interviews, correspondence, and papers relating to twenty-one prominent Michigan conservationists. This background was collected for a book on the subject that was never completed. The audio-tape interviews are located in the Audio tapes series in box 21.
  - Allen, Shirley. Interviewed May 6, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Bartlett, Ilo. Interviewed July 24, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Clark, Horace. Interviewed September 3, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Dana, Samuel Trask. Interviewed October 7, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Earle, G. Harold. Interviewed September 27, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Glassen, H.W. Interviewed February 25, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Gunia, Larry. Interviewed November 17, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Harris, William. Interviewed November 14, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Millar, Charles and Bartlett, Ilo. Interviewed October 18, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (No interview 1956) (Box 20)
  - Pirnie, Miles, Dr. Interviewed September 20, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Raff, George. Interviewed October 11, 19?? (Box 20)
  - Rahilly, Joseph B. Interviewed September 27, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Ruhl, Harold. Interviewed October 12, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Saunders, Carl M. Interviewed October 30, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Slater, Kenneth. Interviewed April 4, 1958 (Box 20)
    No audio tape
  - Smits, Lee. Interviewed May 9, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Stephenson, Joe. Interviewed December 8, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Stewart, Gilbert. Interviewed November 22, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Titus, Harold. Interviewed November 17, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Westerman, Fred. Interviewed September 23, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Notes for proposed history: Prominent Michigan Conservationists (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series (Box 21) contains a second unpublished manuscript by Jack Van Coevering, "How industry fights pollution." Also included are general notes and resources for the proposed history and a bibliography of environmental and conservation literature prepared by Jack Van Coevering
  - "How Industry Fights Pollution" Manuscript by J. Van Coevering 1967 (Box 21)
  - "Looking Backwards in Conservation" Publication by James W. Stuber (Box 21)
  - Bibliography of Environmental and Conservation Literature compiled by J. Van Coevering 1973 (Box 21)
- Audio Tapes
  The Audio Tapes series (Box 21) contains the twenty 7-inch reel-to-reel tapes of the interviews for the proposed history of prominent Michigan conservationists, as well as ten unprocessed reel-to-reel tapes of various sizes and speeds that include assorted game calls and a copy of WUOM's "Conservation Report" from 1969 and 1972.
  - Transcribed Interviews for Prominent Michigan Conservationists, 7-in. reel-to-reel tapes
    (Tapes 19 and 20 not transcribed)
    - Joe Stephenson (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 1)
    - Larry Gunia, Gilbert Stewart, Harold Titus (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 2)
    - Gibert Stewart (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 3)
    - Dr. Paul Herbert (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 4)
    - Dr. Paul Herbert (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 5)
    - G. Harold Earle, William Harris (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 6)
    - Horace Clark, Joseph B. Rahilly (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 7)
    - Shirley Allen, Joseph B. Rahilly (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 8)
    - Harold Rhul (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 9)
    - George Raff (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 10)
    - Ilo Bartlett, Lee Smits (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 11)
    - Dr. Miles Pirnie (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 12)
    - Fred Westerman (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 13)
    - Ben East (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 14)
    - Charles Millar and Ilo Bartlett, Carl M. Saunders (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 15)
    - Louis D. McGregor (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 16)
    - Samuel T. Dana (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 17)
    - H. W. Glassen (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 18)
    - Genevieve Gillette (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 19)
    - Genevieve Gillette (Box 21)
      (Reel no. 20)
  - Miscellaneous Audio Tapes, 10 tapes (Box 21)
    (various sizes and speeds; unprocessed but includes some game calls, bawdy deer camp stories, voice recording of Ernest Thompson Seton, and WUOM "Conservation Report" from 1969 and 1972)